Dhwani Shah | shahdhwanio215@gmail.com | Phone: +1(361)228-4266 | NJ

Summary

Around 3 years of experience in IT industry with Cloud Implementation and Migration, Cloud services, Cloud security, Infrastructure as Code, Containerization/Orchestration, Configuration Management, CI/CD. Configuration Management, Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD) and Release Management. Good at manage hosting plans for AWS Infrastructure, implementing and deploying workloads on AWS virtual machines (VMs).

Education

- Aug 2018 May 2020 | MS in Computer Science | Texas A & M University Kingsville | 3.66 / 4 GPA
- 2013 2017 | BE in Instrumentation & Control | Gujarat Technological University | 7.8 / 10 CGPA

Technical Skills

1 centileur 5 km3	
Programming Languages	Python, Bash, Shell scripting, HTML, CSS, Groovy
Database	MySQL, SQL server, Oracle, Redshift, DynamoDB
Operating Systems	Windows, Unix/Linux, CentOS, Ubuntu
Cloud/ DevOps Tools	AWS, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Jenkins, Bamboo, Git, Github, SVN, Bitbucket, Maven, Ant, Gradle, Chef, Puppet, Ansible, Splunk, Datadog, Nagios, New Relic, Nexus, JFrog, JIRA, Rally
Networking Protocols	TCP/IP, VPC/VPN, subnets

Work Experience

• DevOps Engineer | CareerSoft Solutions | NJ | July 2020 - Present

- Hands on experience in Amazon Web Services, proficient in Configuration and automation using Chef, Jenkins, Ansible & Docker. Having involvement in automating infrastructure IAC provisioning using Terraform on AWS.
- Created Ansible roles in YAML and defined tasks, variables, files, handlers, and templates. Created inventory and configured the Ansible files for parallel deployment in Ansible for automating the Continuous delivery process.
- Responsible for CI/CD process implementation using Jenkins along with Python and Shell scripts to automate routine jobs.
- Assisted internal users of Splunk in designing and maintaining production-quality dashboard. Involved in Creating and managing index, create user, role, Permissions to knowledge objects, also providing user and role access permissions to the other teams.
- Implemented cluster services using Docker and Kubernetes to manage local deployments in Kubernetes by building a self-hosted Kubernetes cluster using Terraform and Ansible and deploying application containers.
- Provisioning servers/instances using infrastructure as code such as Terraform and CloudFormation. Code is stored in a private repository and constantly updated.

• System Administration | Harikrupa Automation Ltd. | Ahmedabad | 2016 - 2017

• Worked on installations, configuration of Linux, Solaris Operating Systems on different hardware environments.

- Created and managed user accounts, security, Access Control Limits(ACL), permissions, disk space and process monitoring in Red hat Linux, CentOS.
- Worked on KVM, installing, configuring Linux VMs.
- Gathering requirements from customers and business partners and design, implement and provide solutions in building the environment.
- Deployed and managed Nagios to monitor system health and patch requirements. Setting up alerts through Nagios for critical system processes and applications as well as system resources.

Projects

• Server less Website | Sep 2019 - March 2020

- In this project, used AWS DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS S3 and AWS Cloud Front. It helps developer to launch the products faster, paves the way for ideal business implementation.
- It is a model which allows the users to write and deploy code without worrying about the backend process, which is done by cloud provider.

• Complete Deployment of DevOps | July 2019 - Sep 2019

- Expertise in setting up enterprise infrastructure on Amazon Web Services (AWS) using services such as Amazon EC2, VPC (NAT, Peering, VPN), IAM, EC2 Container service, Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda, S3, Cloud Front, Code pipeline, Code Deploy, Glacier, RDS, DynamoDB, Elastic Cache, Route 53, Cloud watch, Cloud Formation, Cloud Trial, SNS, SQS, Lambda, API Gateway, AWS Alexa etc.
- Expertise with Configuration management tools- Chef, Puppet and Ansible for Deployment on Multiple platforms. Also, have extensive experience in Hudson/Jenkins, Bamboo for continuous integration and for the end to end automation of builds and scheduled deployments.
- Ability to write scripts in Bash/Shell, PERL, Ruby, Groovy and Python scripting languages.

• Integration of Ansible & AWS | Jan 2019 - April 2019

• Used Ansible to automate the applications in AWS, which greatly increases the chances that cloud initiative will be a success.

• Deployed Kubernetes with Terraform | Jan 2019 - March 2019

• While I can use 'kubectl' or same CLI based tools to manage kubernetes resources, using Terraform has benefits like unified workflow, full lifecycle management and graph of relations.

• CI/CD Pipelines | Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

• Built CI/CD pipeline using Docker and Jenkins. The intention is of DevOps is to create better quality software more quickly and with more reliability while inventing greater communications with the teams.

• Jenkins with Git | Sep 2018 - Oct 2018

• Integrated Jenkins using GitHub Authentication plugin, it is possible to use GitHub's own authentication scheme for implementing authentication in our Jenkins instance.

Extra-Curricular Work

- Certification of Udemy AWS Associate Architect
- Coordinator and Event Organizer for AIS(Association of Indian Students) at TAMUK | 2019
- Event Organizer in the technical festival "HEXON' 17" at GECG | 2017
- Instructor for school students(subjects: Physics, Mathematics) | 2014-2017